I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
I want to go back and finish
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
Konna itami mo kangei jan
So that's Roy Mustang.
The Flame Alchemist, eh?
An exceptional promotion at that age?
I wonder what kind of connections he used.
They say the faster you rise, the faster you fall.
Come in.
Sorry to bother you.
I am Colonel Roy Mustang.
Ah, Colonel Mustang.
I apologize. The Führer President is out right now.
To where?
He went to the South for an inspection.
South?
I don't like this smell.
But it smells familiar.
This is...
I simply came for an inspection,
but it seems I just discovered something.
Those Who Lurk
Underground
Move in!
A brat and a housewife?! How grand.
But I'm kind of ill-matched for a fight.
I'll be making my escape.
You-
M-Master, hang in there!
Running away?! How cowardly...
Master...
Master! Master!!!
Stay...
...still...
N...o...
Greed!
Looks like you're okay, Martel.
What happened? I haven't seen Roa and the others, either...
Yeah, things have become a little complicated.
We have to get out of here somehow.
I can't let you do that.
Huh? Who are you, old man?
Führer President!
Why are you here?
King Bradley?!
So what business does the most powerful guy in the country have with us?
How old are you?
Huh?
I'm turning sixty this year.
When you get old, your body starts to not move the way you want it to.
So I really want to get this over with and go home.
Retire already, gramps.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, you're not just an ordinary geezer, are you?!
Greed?!
Now you've seen it.
A skill that has been passed down in the Armstrong household for generations... Sculpture Alchemy!!!
In that case, I won't hold back.
How strange...
We've ensured the safety of the boy and the housewife.
We'll proceed with the extermination of all the monsters!
It's an order from the Führer President!
It's been a while since anyone's gotten me so excited.
Nothing less to be expected from Sir Armstrong.
I also participated in the Ishbal extermination.
Former ally, eh?
Then all the more reason not to kill you.
Surrender at once.
Even though you're planning on killing me?
Major!
Roa!
Bastard!!!
You see,
I don't have an ultimate shield like you,
nor an ultimate spear that pierces diamond.
Do you understand how someone like that could have survived countless battles,
rendered distinguished service,
and has achieved the rank I have right now?
Y...ou...
Just as you have an ultimate shield,
I have an ultimate eye.
Now, Greed.
How many times do I have to kill you to get rid of you for good?
Where's Greed?
I don't know.
It's too dark; I can't see anything.
Greed?!
No!
Hey! Open up!
Let me out!
I said no!
That was fifteen deaths, wasn't it?
How many more do you have? Hmm?
Y-You bastard...
Dammit...
The Führer President himself is here?
I don't mind if you run off with your tail between your legs.
I'd love to,
but dogs are loyal animals.
Please, get her out of here.
We're counting on you.
Roa?! Dolcetto?!
Hey, quit interfering! Let me out!
I won't!
I don't have time to mess with you!
I'm telling you to open up!
No! You can't come out!
Shut up and open up!
Are you telling me to just sit and watch my friends be killed?!
I can't let you out!
They asked me to keep you safe!
Dolcetto!!!
Roa!!!
Please, I'm begging you...
You can't... come out.
Hey, hey, Mister Bradley.
You really think you'll get away with doing this to my men?
You're feeling sympathetic now? How silly.
Sympathy?
Are you stupid?
Who do you think I am?
I'm Greed.
Money, women, subordinates...
...everything belongs to me!
Which is why I won't abandon what's mine.
I'm a greedy guy, after all!!!
Greedy? This is beyond silly.
How about you lie there for a while.
I have to get out of here...
Hang on.
You're Edward's brother, aren't you?
Are you hurt? Let me lend you a hand.
N-No, I'm fine.
I can go back by myself.
No, Martel!
Bradley!!!
Al!!!
M-Mom!
Mom! Mom!!!
Al! Hang in there!
Hey, say something!
Al!
Brother...
You all right?
You're covered in blood, too, Brother...
I opened you up and pulled her body out.
I couldn't save her...
It's not your fault.
Come on. Let's go back.
Al...
Hold there.
I've got something I need to ask you both.
The mastermind of this incident, Greed. Is he an acquaintance of yours?
No, sir.
Did you happen to obtain
any important information from him?
Nothing that would benefit the army, no.
Don't misunderstand me. Not for the army.
If you were making a deal with them...
...depending on your answer...
Did you ally yourself with people whose intent was to harm the mainstay of the army?
No, sir.
Any other questions?
Your steel arm and your brother's body.
They're related, are they not?
You're an honest one.
Time to withdraw.
Take good care of your little brother, you hear?
I deeply appreciate you saving those two boys.
Don't worry about it.
It's one of the duties of the army to protect State Alchemists, too.
How about it?
Would you like to be protected by the army, too?
Become a State Alchemist?
Precisely.
As you can see, I'm a frail housewife.
Is this country so strained as to require the help of someone like me?
Harsh words!
I'll come again.
You may have changed your mind by then.
That Greed guy had a tattoo of Ouroboros on his hand.
Ouroboros...
You heard me telling Lt. Colonel Hughes, didn't you?
They're people who have something to do with the philosopher's stones.
Sir Hughes...
Edward Elric.
Don't do anything too reckless, all right?
Okay...
Well then...
Brother.
My memories of when my body was taken have returned.
How was it?!
Well...
It was kind of extraordinary...
But I couldn't find anything about human transmutation.
I see...
In the end, no progress, eh...
Not necessarily.
Remember what the Führer President said?
That there have been disquieting activities within the military.
Yeah, he said that it had something to do with philosopher's stones and the people who have tattoos of Ouroboros...
He said he wanted to catch them for that reason, right?
Greed also had that tattoo.
If so, why did he need to kill them all?
If he really wanted to know what they were up to,
he should have captured and interrogated them, right?
You're right.
And besides, it's strange the Führer President himself came to the battlefield when there weren't that many enemies.
Yeah. Everything just seems so fishy.
Guess we'll stick with the army for a little longer.
Welcome back, Führer President.
How did the inspection of the South go?
The Fullmetal Alchemist's brother...
...and perhaps their master, too.
Both of them may also be suitable sacrifices.
I also found something else that was unexpected.
Oh my, now that's someone I haven't seen in a while.
He left this place a century ago.
Wake up, Greed.
Oh wow, looks like everyone's here.
So much for your ultimate shield.
You look as gorgeous as you did a century ago.
Miss Lust, the "Ultimate Spear".
And Gluttony, you haven't lost weight at all.
And, Envy? You still dress like that?
Where's Sloth at?
He always skips out on meetings.
He's working right now.
Seriously, none of you guys have changed over a hundred years.
And who's this guy?
I am Wrath.
Wrath?
Aren't you King Bradley?
Yup. He's our last sibling Father created as a human by the name of King Bradley.
An aging Homunculus?!
Is that even possible?
"There's no way there's no way."
I thought that was a stock phrase of yours. Don't tell me you forgot?
Or are you going senile?
Shut your mouth, you ugly shit.
What was that?
Hey, I like those eyes. That's the way you ought to be.
How about you show your true colors every once in a while, Envy the Bizarre.
You piece of shit...
I'll kick your ass, if that's what you're asking for.
Cut it out, all of you.
Please don't fight among siblings, especially in front of your father.
Yo, old man.
Looks like you've aged a lot since the last time I saw you.
Greed.
You are my son who shares my soul.
Why did you betray me?
"Why"?
Shouldn't you know best?
I am Greed.
That's how you gave me life, and that's the way I've lived.
If I stayed by your side, I wouldn't be able to obtain everything my greedy soul desires.
Will you work for me again?
No can do!
I see...
I really don't like your tastes...
This is how hot I like my baths, damnit!
I'm sure the flames of Hell are hotter than this!
I'll go on ahead to see what it's like, my siblings!
Go back to where you came from, my soul, Greed!
You don't even have to ask!!!
Don't blame me if you get a stomachache, old man!!!
To the forthcoming day,
I pray for the unchanging loyalty of you all, along with peace and order.
Dad!
Welcome back, Dad!
Thank you, Selim.
How was the inspection?
It was a substantial inspection all right.
Dear, you're getting older...
Why not give up your position to a junior and relax?
No, no, I'm still in my prime.
Oh, that's right. I met the
Fullmetal Alchemist while in the South.
The short alchemist? Really?!
You really love hearing about Mr. Edward, don't you, Selim?
He's the youngest State Alchemist! That's just so cool!
That's awesome. I want to learn alchemy, too!
What in the world would you do with it?
I want to get a state qualification to be useful to Dad.
Then I might ask for your help in the future.
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
Futari arukidasu
The pebbles foreigners throw into the water create ripples, and as they link together, they create a huge whirlpool.
Look! That's precisely what's happening right now.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
The Envoy from
the East
Episode 15, Envoy From the East.
I hide my blade behind my smile
and seek the Philosopher's Stone.